Guide to the Cornell Injection Molding Program records, 1974-2002.
Cornell Injection Molding Program records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Injection Molding Program records, 1974-2002.
16-5-3929
Cornell University.Cornell Injection Molding Program (CIMP).
6 cubic feet.
Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes technical and progress reports, conference and journal papers and technical manuals related to the Cornell Injection Molding Program.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1970 Cornell hired K.K. Wang in the Dept. of Mechanical System and Design, who submitted a proposal to RANN (Research Applied for National Needs) to develop some scientific basis for mold design and process control. The RANN program invited industrial participation in its reveiw process, and Kodak and Xerox supported Wang's proposal. In 1974 the proposal was accepted and the NSF/RANN grant continued through 1979. After that the program was supported by NSF with a total of 11 grants from 1974-1998.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes technical and progress reports, conference and journal papers and technical manuals related to the Cornell Injection Molding Program.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Wang, K.K.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.College of Engineering.; Cornell University.Dept. of Mechanical System and Design.; Eastman Kodak Company.; National Science Foundation (U.S.); Research Applied for National Needs (RANN); Xerox Corporation.
Subjects:
Injection molding of plastics.; Plastics
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Progress Reports 1-21, January 1975-March 2000 (Box 1)
- Technical Reports 1-50, September 1974-August 1985 (Box 2)
- Technical Reports 51-76, July 1984-January 1994 (Box 3)
- Technical Reports 77-93, January 1994-December 2002 (Box 4)
- Technical Manuals 1-13, November 1979-November 1997 (Box 4)
- CIMP Consortium Meeting Notes, May 30, 1984-November 6, 1991 (Box 4)
- CIMP Consortium Meeting Notes, May 27, 1992-June 18, 1999 (Box 5)
- Journal and Conference Paper Reprints 1-101 (Including index of the reprints), 1975-1989 (Box 5)
- Journal and Conference Paper Reprints 102-199, 1989-2001 (Box 6)
- National Science Foundation Die-Casting Papers 1-10 (Including index of papers), 1989-1996 (Box 6)
- Friction Welding Papers 1-4 (Including index of papers), 1974-1982 (Box 6)
- Geometric Modelling Papers 1-14 (Including index of papers, 1980-1995 (Box 6)
- CIMP at Fifteen, CIMP at Twenty-Publications, 1989; 1994 (Box 6)
- Articles about CIMP, 1976; 1982; 1994 (Box 6)
- History of CIMP-written by K.K. Wang, 2011 (Box 6)
- CIMP Meeting Tapes 1-3 (VHS), January 8 1995 (Box 6)